Guide to the Frederick H. Smyth Collection of Fire Photographs 1899-1926 (Bulk 1908-1914) PR 63
New-York Historical Society
- Series I: Albums
  - Fire Department horseshoe wagon outside firehouse, 120 West 83rd Street (Negative 106115-106116), 1909 (Page 75)
  - Fire Department horseshoe wagon outside firehouse, 120 West 83rd Street (Negative 106117-106118), 1909 (Page 77)
  - Fire Department horse (Negatives 106119-106120), 1913 (Page 79)
  - Firehouse interior, Hook and Ladder Company 25 wagon, 205 West 77th Street (Negative 410572), 1906 (Page 81)
  - Firehouse interior, Hook & Ladder Company 25 hitching up horses to wagon, 205 West 77th Street (Negative 410573), 1906 (Page 81)
  - Hook and Ladder Company 25 raising ladder, 205 West 77th Street (Negatives 410574-410575), 1908 (Page 83)
  - Firehouse interior, apparatus floor, Engine Company 76, 105 West 102nd Street (Negatives 410576-410577), 1906-1907 (Page 85)
  - Firehouse interior, bunk room, Engine Company 76, 105 West 102 Street (Negative 410578), 1904 (Page 87)
  - Engine Company 74 on the way to a fire, West 78th Street & Broadway (Negative 410579), 1904 (Page 87)
  - Firehouse exterior, Engine Company 31, 87 Lafayette Street (Negative 410580), 1908 (Page 89)
  - Firehouse interior, bunk room, Hook and Ladder Company 7, (Negative 410581), 1906 (Page 89)
  - Firehouse interior, recreation floor, Hook & Ladder Company 7, (Negatives 410582-410583), 1906 (Page 91)
  - Firehouse interior, recreation floor, Hook & Ladder Company 7, (Negative 410584), 1906 (Page 93)
  - Firehouse interior, fireman on house watch (Negative 410585), 1906 (Page 93)
  - Interior of Gansevoort Street High-Pressure Pumping Station, Gansevoort & West Streets (Negatives 106160-106161), 1910 (Page 95)
  - Interior of Gansevoort Street High-Pressure Pumping Station, Gansevoort & West Streets (Negatives 106162-106163), 1910 (Page 97)
  - Interior of Gansevoort Street High-Pressure Pumping Station, Gansevoort & West Streets (Negatives 106164-1061650, 1910 (Page 99)
  - High-Pressure Fire Engine (Negative 106166), 1909 (Page 101)
  - High-Pressure Pumping System test, Pier 51 (Negative 106167), 1909 (Page 101)
  - High-Pressure Pumping System test, West & Bank Streets (Negative 106168), 1908 (Page 103)
  - High-Pressure Pumping System test, Union Square (Negative 106169), 1910 (Page 103)
  - High-Pressure Pumping System test, West & Bank Streets, (Negatives 106170-106171), 1908 (Page 105)
  - High-Pressure Pumping System test, West & Bank Streets, (Negatives 106172-106173), 1908 (Page 107)
  - High-Pressure Pumping System test, West & Bank Streets, (Negative 106174), 1908 (Page 109)
  - Engine Company 56, firemen and wagon outside of firehouse, 120 West 83rd Street (Negative 106175), 1908 (Page 109)
  - High-Pressure fire hydrant with hoses attached (Negative 263058) (Page 111)
  - Fire Patrol 5, firemen outside firehouse (Negative 263059) (Page 111)
  - Engine Company 93, exterior of firehouse, 513 West 181 Street (Negative 263070) (Page 113)
  - Crowd at factory fire (Negative 263071) (Page 113)
  - Municipal Parade, Chief of Fire Department and aides (Negative 263072), 1910 (Page 113)
  - Detail of a pump at the High Pressure Pumping Station, Gansevoort and West Streets (Negative 263073) (Page 113)
  - Water tower in action at a fire (Negative 263074) (Page 115)
  - Wallpaper Factory Fire, West 34th Street & Eleventh Avenue (Negative 263075), 1909 (Page 115)
  - Fire alarm station, interior (Negative 263076) (Page 115)
  - Engine Company 56, firemen and wagons outside firehouse, 120 West 83rd Street (Negatives 106176-106177), 1907 (Page 117)
  - Engine Company 56, firemen and wagon outside firehouse, 120 West 83rd Street (Negative 106178), 1907 (Page 119)
  - Engine Company 56 on the way to a fire (Negative 106179), 1907 (Page 119)
  - Engine Company 56 on the way to a fire (Negative 106180), 1907 (Page 121)
  - Engine Company 83, Bronx (Negative 106181) (Page 121)
  - Engine Company 83, Bronx (Negatives 106182-106183), 1910 (Page 123)
  - Engine Company 83, Bronx (Negative 106184) (Page 125)
  - Engine Company 35, 223 East 119th Street (Negative 106185), 1910 (Page 125)
  - Auto fire engine at hydrant (Negative 255344), 1925 (Page 127)
  - Fire surgeon at work (Negative 255345), 1925 (Page 127)
  - High-Pressure Hose Company 30, Pier 35 (Negative 106187), 1910 (Page 129)
  - High-Pressure Hose Company 30, Pier 35 (Negatives 106188-106189), 1910 (Page 131)
  - High-Pressure Hose Company 30, Pier 35 (Negative 106190), 1910 (Page 133)
  - High-Pressure Hose Company 72, 22 East 12th Street (Negative 106191), 1911 (Page 133)
  - High-Pressure Hose Company 72, 22 East 12th Street (Negatives 106192-106193), 1911 (Page 135)
  - Firehouse exterior, Engine Company 93 and Hook & Ladder 45, 513 181st Street (Negative 106194) (Page 137)
  - Engine Company 93, firemen and two fire engines, on Washington (Heights) Bridge (Page 137)
  - Engine Company 93, firemen and two fire engines outside firehouse, 513 West 181st Street (Negatives 106196-106197) (Page 139)
  - Engine Company 93, firemen and two fire engines, Washington (Heights) Bridge (Negative 106198) (Page 141)
  - Engine Company 7, high-pressure service, firemen and fire engine, 100 Duane Street (Negative 106199) (Page 141)
  - Engine Company 7, high-pressure service, firemen and fire engine outside firehouse, 100 Duane Street (Negatives 106200-106201) (Page 143)
  - Hook & Ladder Company 2, firehouse exterior, 126 East 50th Street (Negative 106202) (Page 145)
  - Hook & Ladder Company 2, firehouse interior, 129 East 50th Street (Negative 106203) (Page 145)
  - Hook & Ladder Company 2, firemen and fire engine outside firehouse, 126 East 50th Street, (Negatives 106204-106205) (Page 147)
  - Hook & Ladder Company 2, firemen and fire engine, 126 East 50th Street (Negatives 106206-106207) (Page 149)
  - Fire Patrol 4, 120 West 83rd Street (Negative 106208) (Page 151)
  - Water Tower 1, firemen with apparatus, 87 Lafayette Street (Negative 106209) (Page 151)
  - Water Tower 1, firemen with apparatus, 87 Lafayette Street (Negative 106210) (Page 153)
  - Model Steam Fire Engine (Negative 106211), 1906 (Page 153)
  - Model Steam Fire Engine (Negative 106212-106213), 1906 (Page 155)
  - Model Steam Fire Engine (Negative 106214-106215), 1906 (Page 157)
  - Model Steam Fire Engine (Negative 106216), 1906 (Page 159)
  - Model Firehouse (Negative 106217), 1911 (Page 159)
  - City Budget Exhibit, Volunteer Fire Engines (Negative 106218), 1911 (Page 161)
  - City Budget Exhibit, Map showing locations of firehouses (Negative 106219), 1911 (Page 161)
  - City Budget Exhibit, Chart showing appropriations for Fire Department (Negative 106220), 1911 (Page 163)
  - City Budget Exhibit, Display showing budget appropriations since consolidation (Negative 106221), 1911 (Page 163)
  - City Budget Exhibit, Map showing locations of firehouses (Negatives 106222-106223), 1911 (Page 165)
  - City Budget Exhibit, Municipal Explosives Commission display (Negative 106224), 1911 (Page 167)
  - City Budget Exhibit, Division of Apparatuus and Repair Shop Supplies diplay (Negative 106225), 1911 (Page 167)
  - City Budget Exhibit, Auto fire engine remodeled by the Fire Department Repair Shop (Negative 106266), 1911 (Page 169)
  - City Budget Exhibit, display showing 185 years of fire apparatus development (Negative 106227), 1911 (Page 169)
  - Hook & Ladder Company 26 (Negative 244650) (Page 171)
  - Fire engine on way to fire, [West] 58th Street (Negative 244651) (Page 171)
  - Fire Patrol 5, West 120th Street (Negatives 244652-244653) (Page 171)
  - Fire Patrol 5, West 120th Street (Negative 244654) (Page 173)
  - Engine Company 76 on way to a fire (Negatives 244655-244656), 1914 (Page 173)
  - High-Pressure Pumping Station, Gansevoort Street (Negative 244657) (Page 173)
  - Dedication of Firemen's Monument at 100th Street & Riverside Drive (Negative 263056), Sept. 5, 1913 (Page 175)
  - Ice-coated ruins of a building fire (Negative 263057) (Page 175)
  - Funeral of a fireman killed in a fire (Negative 259125), 1926 (Page 177)
  - Engine Company 39 and Hook & Ladder Company 16 firehouse, 157-159 East 67th Street (Negative 259126), 1926 (Page 177)
  - Fire Department Medal Ceremony (Negative 263164), 1908 (Page 179)
- Series II: Negatives
  This series includes 405 negatives. Fifty of these are film, the remainder are glass, primarily 5 x 7 inches. Smyth numbered each in the emulsion. The negatives are filed numerically and, as mentioned above, this order does not correspond to the page numbering system in the albums of prints. Thirty images are glass transparencies or autochromes, and therefore do not have corresponding prints in Series I. These are interfiled numerically with the negatives.
  - Numbers 106107 - 106139, 1906-1913, undated (Box 3)
  - Numbers 106140 - 106170, 1908-1916 (Box 4)
  - Numbers 106171 - 106205, 1907-1911, undated (Box 5)
  - Numbers 106206 - 106240, 1906-1913, undated (Box 6)
  - Numbers 106241 - 106275, 1909-1914, undated (Box 7)
  - Numbers 106276 - 106305, 1911-1913, undated (Box 8)
  - Numbers 106306 - 106340, 1909-1914, undated (Box 9)
  - Numbers 106341 - 106354, 244634 - 244660, 1904-1914, undated (Box 10)
  - Numbers 244661 - 244715, 1904-1920, undated (Box 11)
  - Numbers 244716 - 244726, 254839 - 254841, 255344 - 255345, 259125 - 259126, 263056 - 263076, 263164, 1899-1926, undated (Box 12)
  - Numbers 410558 - 410596, 1899-1909, undated (Box 13)